PIASY XU

ANDROID ENGINEER

Profile

I'm Piasy (建林、许). I receive my Bachelor degree on Computer Science in Tsinghua University at 2015. Now I'm leading the Android team at YOLO, a mobile live streaming App. I appreciate technology, and enjoy dealing real-life challenge with technology. Now I'm focusing on Android application development, but my sight will never be limited in it. I think solving valuable problems with team members, efficiently and reliably, is the most important thing when building a product. To achieve this, critical thinking, ability to learn new things, and collaborating with others are key points. My dev blog is http://blog.piasy.com/, and my GitHub profile is https://github.com/Piasy/.

Skills

Android Development

2 years experience on App development, with practice about architecture, TDD, reactive programming(I'm RxJava fan), RESTful API call, local data management, custom view and interaction, and performance tuning.

Project management

Some experience on project management, including task scheduling, team member collaborating, improving workflow, CI and CD, code quality, code review and progressive refactoring.

Golang web backend

Some experience about building RESTful API server, TDD and database design. I'v built two RESTful API servers with Beego framework, storing data in MongoDB and MySQL database, deployed at Aliyun cloud.

Technical

Android Development

Java

Beego

Experience

Beijing Youluoshidai Technology Co., Ltd. (Startup)

Android Engineer 2015.05-now

- 1. Design, develop and maintain the company App Android client: YOLO, a mobile live streaming App.
- 2. Participate the project from scratch, including prototyping, Android client architecture design and improvement, backend architecture improvement, and evolvement of the whole company.
- 3. Build and lead the Android team, continuously delivering our Android App.
- 4. Refactor the essential part of Android project, follow the best practice of OOP and design pattern.
- 5. Keep improving my knowledge on Android platform, and become a fan of open source, innovation, and knowledge sharing. Giving a public talk about Android model layer architecture at GDG Android Meetup

6. Learn about procedure of backend API development and deployment.

Keywords: Network layer architecture. Model layer architecture. YaMvp. IM integration. Camera input(open source soon). Voice input and output. TDD. OkBuck. AndroidTDDBootStrap. Understand great libraries. Entrepreneurship is hard

XueBa(Beijing) technology development Co., LTD (Startup)

R&D Internship 2014.10-2015.03

- 1. Develop and maintain the Android client of college student social App: Young;
- 2. Android automated UI testing(using Espresso test kit);
- $3. \ My \ first time attending production project, the moving fast style meets my pursuing of technical skill very well. And I also learn about how startup works.$
- 4. Dependency injection, reactive programming, and RESTful API... all those modern developing ways catch me up.
- 5. Introduce automated testing into project, build reliable App more efficiently.

Keywords: automated testings reactive programmings dependency injections RESTful APIs agile developments moving fast

Baidu, Inc.

R&D Internship

2014.08-2014.10

- 1. Maintain a log service system: pipal;
- 2. Understand the Service Oriented Flyweight Architecture system: sofa;
- 3. Learn about how big company in China works, and the daily workflow of them.
- 4. Their weekly internal knowledge sharing is really great!

Keywords: big company, knowledge sharing

Open Source

And roid TDD Boot Strap

An Android TDD bootstrap project, with well designed architecture and collection of awesome libraries, including TDD / code coverage / CI / code quality integration. Aiming to be a good start point of new project, with practice and feedback from two production project.

OkBuck

A Gradle plugin, help Android developers to utilize the super fast build system BUCK with several lines configuration. It has been transferred to Uber at Sep. 2016.

RxAndroidAudio

Android Audio API encapsulation library, with part Rx support, maybe the most robust Android Audio API encapsulation library.

SafelyAndroid

Build safely Android App, no more Activity not found, Activity state loss and NPE during fragment transaction!

AdvancedRxJava

 $The \ Chinese \ translation \ of \ blog \ series \ Advanced \ Reactive \ Java \ http://akarnokd.blogspot.com/.$

Education

Tsinghua University

Bachelor degree on Computer Science

2011-2015

2nd freshman award of 2011 grade, rewarding the top 5 student of each province in the College Entrance Exam; attending courses including Data structure, Design pattern, Computer Network, Operating System, Introduction to Search Engine, Service Oriented Archtecture, etc. GPA is 92.1 in 100, top 9 students in 129; doing research in lab about mobile App sucurity analyse and mobile cloud storage optimization, publishing one paper on Tsinghua Science and Technology, with 22 citations by middle 2016.